Dear Human Resources at Conversant,

I am responding to the job posting on your website for a Marketing Web Developer. My broad skill set runs the gamut from programming and web development to graphic design and animation.

Currently, I am the Web and Graphic Designer for family-owned plastics manufacturer AGT Products, Inc. I am the only member of my department, and therefore wear many hats. All of the design work for the company, web and print, is created by me.

During my time as a lone designer at AGT, it has been a rewarding experience to teach myself a number of necessary skills and technologies. Some of these include React, Redux, AngularJS, Angular2, LESS, and SASS to name a few. The most fulfilling project I have done for AGT was building the AGT Tapes division website (agttapes.com) from scratch using AngularJS and SASS with a SQL database on the back-end.

But my proudest technical achievement overall as a web developer was designing and coding my personal portfolio site (mattbsmith.com). I built the site using React and Redux along with Adobe Illustrator and After Effects to create a hybrid of a website, a game, and cartoon. Working on my portfolio site helped me grow to new levels in every skill involved in its creation.

As for my education, I received an AAS in Graphic Design and a Certificate of Achievement in Web Design from Waubonsee Community College in 2015. I graduated with a a perfect 4.0 GPA and my outstanding academic status earned me scholarships from the Lifelong Learning Institute and Weblinx, Inc.

At my core, I am an idea man. I have always excelled at merging disparate concepts to create new ones that can solve complex and unique problems. Between my innate creativity and robust set of skills, I believe I would make an excellent addition to the Conversant team. Thank you for your time in considering me for the Senior Front-End Developer position.

Sincerely, Matthew Brubaker Smith

3532 McCormick Ave. Unit 1 Brookfield, IL 60513 571.334.5613 matt@mattbsmith.com mattbsmith.com

Matthew Brubaker Smith

Front-End Developer • Graphic Designer



Experience

AGT Products, Inc.

Web & Graphic Designer

(Addison, IL) March 2016 - Present

- Developed agttapes.com, front & back-end (AngularJS/Sass/SQL)
- Created all marketing and informational materials (Print & Web)
- Updated/Organized massive product database

Batavia Main Street

Freelance Graphic Designer

- Farmers' Market Logo
- General Events Poster (2014)
- Ladies Night Out (Logo/Poster/Flyer)
- BatFest Event Poster (2014)

Additional Freelance Work

Franciscan Outreach

(Chicago, IL)

(Batavia, IL)

2014 - 2015

Takin' It to the Streets Event (Invitation/Program)

2014

Security Partners Guard Services

..., 15

(Lombard, IL)

(Sugar Grove, IL)

WordPress Website (securitypartnersguardservice.com)

2015

Education

Waubonsee Community College

AAS - Graphic Design

COA - Web Design

- Graduated with a 4.0 GPA
- Recipient of Lifelong Learning Institute & Weblinx, Inc. scholarships

Skills

Technical

- HTML/CSS
- LESS/SASS
- WordPress
- Javascript/ ¡Query
- GitHub
- AngularJS/2
- React/Redux

January 2014 - December 2015

- NPM/Webpack
- PHP/SQL

Creative

- Illustrator
- InDesign

- Photoshop
- Illustration
- After Effects
- Photography

Personal

- Communication
- Marketing
- Leadership
- Public Speaking
- Customer Service
- Copywriting

nattbsmith.com